<luach>
<item>
<title>Erev Rosh Hashanah</title>
<section name="Customs of the day">
<li>It is customary for synagogues to replace the Torah cover, Parochet (curtain covering the Ark), and cover of the reading table with white ones until after Yom Kippur.</li>
<li>It is customary to visit the graves of loved ones on this day.</li>
</section>

<section name="Shacharit">
<li>We do not sound the shofar during Shacharit.</li>
<li>Conclude the service with Achat Sha’alti (MT 662)</li>
</section>

<section name="Erev Rosh Hashanah Candlelighting">
<li>Light candles before sunset.</li>
<li>Recite the festival candle blessing and Shehecheyanu (MT 384)</li>
</section>

<section name="During Rosh Hashanah dinner">
  <li>We recite the Kiddush for Rosh Hashanah evening, followed by Shehecheyanu.</li>
  <li>Before making HaMotzi, dip an apple in honey and recite the following:
  <ul>
    <li><em>Y’hi ratzon mil’fanecha, Adonai Eloheinu v’Elohei avoteinu v’imoteinu, she’t’chadeish aleinu shanah tova um’tukah.</em></li>
    <li>May it be your will, Adonai our God and God of our ancestors, to renew us for a good and sweet year.</li>
  </ul></li>
  <li>Then, recite the blessing over fruit:
  <ul>
    <li><em>Baruch ata Adonai, Eloheinu melech ha’olam, borei p’ri ha’eitz.</em></li>
    <li>Blessed are you, Adonai our God, Sovereign of the universe, who creates the fruit of the tree.</li>
  </ul></li>
  <li>Eat the apple.</li>
  <li>We then make Hamotzi over two Challot.  It is customary to eat round challot during this season.  Some people sprinkle honey over their challah rather than salt.</li>
  <li>We add Ya’aleh v’Yavo and Harachaman for Rosh Hashanah to Birkat Hamazon.</li>
</section>
</item>
<item>
<title>Aseret Y'mei T'shuvah</title>
<section name="default">
During the Aseret Y'mei T'shuvah (10 days of repentance between Rosh Hashanah through Yom Kippur)
Traditionally, congregations continue reciting S'lichot each morning before shacharit.
When reciting every Kaddish, after the word "l'eilah," we add "u'l'eilah."
When reciting the Amidah, include passages marked "Between Rosh Hashanah and Yom Kippur."
We continue to conclude our Shacharit and Ma'ariv services with Achat Sha'alti (MT 662)
</section>
</item>
</luach>
