<luach>
<item>
<title>Erev Rosh Hashana</title>
<section name="Customs of the day">
<li>It is customary for synagogues to replace the Torah cover, Parochet (curtain covering the Ark), and cover of the reading table with white ones until after Yom Kippur.</li>
<li>It is customary to visit the graves of loved ones on this day.</li>
</section>

<section name="Shacharit">
<li>We do not sound the shofar during Shacharit.</li>
<li>Conclude the service with Achat Sha’alti (MT 662)</li>
</section>

<section name="Erev Rosh Hashanah Candlelighting">
<li>Light candles before sunset.</li>
<li>Recite the festival candle blessing and Shehecheyanu (MT 384)</li>
</section>

<section name="During Rosh Hashanah dinner">
  <li>We recite the Kiddush for Rosh Hashanah evening, followed by Shehecheyanu.</li>
  <li>Before making HaMotzi, dip an apple in honey and recite the following:</li>
  <li>Y’hi ratzon mil’fanecha, Adonai Eloheinu v’Elohei avoteinu v’imoteinu, she’t’chadeish aleinu shanah tova um’tukah.</li>
  <li>May it be your will, Adonai our God and God of our ancestors, to renew us for a good and sweet year.</li>
  <li>Then, recite the blessing over fruit:</li>
  <li>Baruch ata Adonai, Eloheinu melech ha’olam, borei p’ri ha’eitz.</li>
  <li>Blessed are you, Adonai our God, Sovereign of the universe, who creates the fruit of the tree.</li>
  <li>Eat the apple.</li>
  <li>We then make Hamotzi over two Challot.  It is customary to eat round challot during this season.  Some people sprinkle honey over their challah rather than salt.</li>
  <li>We add Ya’aleh v’Yavo and Harachaman for Rosh Hashanah to Birkat Hamazon.</li>
</section>
</item>
<item>
<title>Aseret Y'mei T'shuvah</title>
<description>10 days of repentance between Rosh Hashanah through Yom Kippur</description>
<section name="default">
<li>Traditionally, congregations continue reciting S'lichot each morning before shacharit.</li>
<li>When reciting every Kaddish, after the word "l'eilah," we add "u'l'eilah."</li>
<li>When reciting the Amidah, include passages marked "Between Rosh Hashanah and Yom Kippur."</li>
<li>We continue to conclude our Shacharit and Ma'ariv services with Achat Sha'alti (MT 662)</li>
</section>
</item>
<item>
<title>Rosh Hashana</title>
<section name="During Rosh Hashanah Lunch">
<li>Recite the Kiddush for Rosh Hashanah day</li>
<li>Some dip apples into honey (others do this only on Rosh Hashanah evening).  For the ritual, see Rosh Hashanah evening</li>
<li>Make Hamotzi over two round challot.</li>
<li>Add Ya'aleh v'Yavo and Harachaman for Rosh Hashanah to Birkat Hamazon</li>
</section>

<section name="Tashlich">
<li>We hold the Tashlich ceremony in the afternoon at a natural body of water.</li>
<li>This ritual is based on Micah 7:18-20, and many congregations recite these verses as part of the ceremony.</li>
</section>

<section name="2nd Day Candlelighting">
<li>We place a new fruit on the table during candlelighting and Kiddush.  When we recite Shehecheyanu during candlelighting and Kiddush, we have in mind that we are reciting it over the new fruit as well.</li>
<li>After dark, we light candles. We recite the festival candle blessing and Shehecheyanu (MT 384)</li>
</section>

<section name="Rosh Hashanah Dinner">
<li>Recite Kiddush for Rosh Hashanah evening, followed by Shehecheyanu.</li>
<li>We then say a blessing over the new fruit and eat it.</li>
<li>Make Hamotzi over two round challot.</li>
<li>Add Ya'aleh V'Yavo and Harachaman for Rosh Hashanah to Birkat Hamazon</li>
</section>
</item>

<item>
<title>Tzom Gedaliah</title>
<description>Tzom Gedalyiah commemorates the assassination of Gedaliah ben Ahikam.  After the Babylonians conquered Jerusalem and destroyed the First Temple in 586 BCE, King Nebuchadnezzar appointed Gedalyah as governor of Judah.  Gedalyah’s assassination a few months later marked the end of Jewish self-government in Jerusalem and the dispersion of the Jews remaining in Jerusalem.</description>
<section name="Customs of the day">
<li>This is a minor fast day.  For those who choose to fast, the fast begins at sunrise and ends at sunset.</li>
<li>Many liberal Jews do not fast on the three minor fast days connected to the Temple, Shiva Asar b’Tammuz, Asara b’Tevet, and Tzom Gedaliah.  Rabbi David Golinkin has written a responsum on this matter; he concludes that these three fast days should be considered optional, in recognition of the redemptive possibilities of the rebirth of the State of Israel.  We should, however, fast on Tish’a b’Av, in order to acknowledge that we are still far from peace.  See Golinkin, David. “Should We Continue to Fast on Tisha B’Av and the Other Three Fasts Which Commemorate the Destruction of the Temple?” Responsa in a Moment 4, no.7 (2010).</li>
</section>
<section name="Shacharit">
<li>When reciting every Kaddish, after the word "l'eilah," we add "u'l'eilah."</li>
<li>When reciting the Amidah, include passages marked, "Between Rosh Hashanah and Yom Kippur"</li>
<li>We add a Torah service to Shacharit (MT 104).  We chant the Torah reading for public fast days.</li>
<li>Torah Reading - Exodus 32:11-14 (Plaut 588), 34:1-10 (Plaut 593)</li>
<li>3 Aliyot</li>
<li>There is a special custom regarding the chanting of the following:</li>
<li>o   32:12 (“Shuv mei’charon . . . l’amecha”)</li>
<li>o   34:6-7 (“Adonai Adonai . . . v’nakei”)</li>
<li>o   34:9 (“v’salachta . . . u’n’chaltanu”)</li>
<li>When the reader reaches these verses, the congregation recites the verses first.  The reader then repeats them in High Holy Day cantillation.  The rest of the portion is read in regular Torah cantillation.</li>

<li>Conclude the service with Achat Sha'alti (MT 662)</li>
</section>
</item>

<item>
<title>Erev Yom Kippur</title>
<section name="General Practices of the Day">
<li>We ask forgiveness from others in preparation for Yom Kippur</li>
<li>Some have the tradition of immersing in a Mikveh in preparation for Yom Kippur</li>
</section>

<section name="Shacharit">
<li>Omit Psalm 100 (MT 51)</li>
<li>When reciting every Kaddish, after the word "l'eilah," we add "u'l'eilah."</li>
<li>When reciting the Amidah, include passages marked, "Between Rosh Hashanah and Yom Kippur"</li>
</section>

<section name="S'udah Mafseket">
<li>In the afternoon, before Yom Kippur begins, it is a Mitzvah to eat a S'udah Mafseket.  This should be a festive and satisfying meal.</li>
<li>* This meal is not only in preparation for the fast to follow, but also to express our hopes that our Yom Kippur observance will lead us to a good new year (JL 123).  Our tradition teaches us that, just as it is a Mitzvah to fast on Yom Kippur, it is also a Mitzvah to eat the day before Yom Kippur.  It should be a festive meal, as Erev Yom Kippur is considered a partially festive day: we express our confidence that God with treat us mercifully this Yom Kippur.</li>
</section>

<section name="Candle Lighting">
<li>Light candles before sunset.  Recite the candle blessing for Yom Kippur, as well as Shehecheyanu</li>
</section>

<section name="Kol Nidre">
<li>We wear tallitot for the Kol Nidre service.</li>
<li>It is customary to wear white for all Yom Kippur services.  Some wear a kittel.</li>
</section>
</item>

<item>
<title>Yom Kippur (on Shabbat)</title>
<section name="Traditional Prohibitions of Yom Kippur">
<li>Eating and drinking</li>
<li>Bathing</li>
<li>Sexual relations</li>
<li>Using oils or lotions</li>
<li>Weating leather shoes</li>
</section>
<section name="Shacharit">
<li>We make changes for Shabbat as marked in the Machzor</li>
</section>
<section name="Torah reading options for morning and afternoon">
<li>Note that the morning reading is traditionally broken into 7 Aliyot (since Yom Kippur falls on Shabbat), and that the afternoon reading is broken into 3 Aliyot.</li>
<li>1. Leviticus 16:1-34 &amp; Numbers 29:7-29:11 (Traditional morning reading)</li>
<li>2. Leviticus 18:1-30 (Traditional afternoon reading)</li>
<li>3. Genesis 50:14-26 </li>
<li>4. Leviticus 16:29-34 and/or Leviticus 19:1-18, 32-37</li>
</section>
<section name="Neilah">
<li>Because Yom Kippur falls on Shabbat, we recite a full Havdalah.</li>
<li>* Typically, the paragraph “Hinei El Y’shuati” and the blessing over spices are omitted from Havdalah after Yom Kippur.  When Yom Kippur falls on Shabbat, we include these elements.</li>
</section>
<section name="After Yom Kippur">
<li>There is a tradition to begin building your Sukkah immediately after breaking your fast.</li>
<li>*We perform a Mitzvah immediately after Yom Kippur is over to show that our repentance on Yom Kippur was genuine.  (See JL 124).</li>
</section>
</item>
</luach>
